<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>me.sergiotarxz.JapaChar</id>
  
  <name>Japachar</name>
  <summary>Learn Japanese characters</summary>
  
  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>AGPL-3.0-only</project_license>
  
  <supports>
    <control>pointing</control>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>touch</control>
  </supports>

  <url type="homepage">https://japachar.sergiotarxz.me</url>

<content_rating type="oars-1.1">
    <content_attribute id="language-humor">mild</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-contacts">intense</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="money-purchasing">intense</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="money-advertising">intense</content_attribute>
</content_rating>

<branding>
  <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#c76dbf</color>
  <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#5d1b52</color>
</branding>


  <developer_name>sergiotarxz</developer_name>
<releases>
  <release version="v2.00-rc3" date="2025-07-25">
    <description>
        <p>Updating to gnome 49 runtime in flathub.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v2.00-rc2" date="2025-07-25">
    <description>
        <p>Improving words population in db in memory constrained environments…</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v2.00-rc1" date="2025-07-24">
    <description>
        <p>Adding words support.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v1.18" date="2025-07-06">
    <description>
        <p>Updating the Perl libraries.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v1.17" date="2025-07-06">
    <description>
        <ul>
            <li>If you are using in linux phones scales over 200% will stop being supported soon since they are a pain to develop for, in phosh you can change this in the display settings.</li>
            <li>Minor font size fixes, pretty much still not completely fixed, sorry.</li>
            <li>Removing learning ON and KUN pronunciations since it is a useless way to memorize Kanji. Sorry, no radicals yet, I am not quite sure yet about how I will support them…</li>
            <li>I need your help to continue improving Japachar, if you are used to the GTK and the GNOME ecosystem get in contact in sergiotarxz@owlcode.tech over XMPP.</li>
            <li>I need a Job as Perl, C, C++, Javascript, Typescript, Java or Kotlin Developer, I am located in Spain, if you know about someone hiring or you are hiring yourself please get in contact too.</li>
        </ul>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v1.16" date="2025-04-29">
    <description>
        <p>Fixing grid.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v1.15" date="2025-04-29">
    <description>
        <p>Sizes were wrong in v1.14.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v1.14" date="2025-04-29">
    <description>
        <p>Avoiding UI overflow in OnePlus 6 with Phosh, my new phone. Just hoping the outage in Spain allows me to push.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v1.13" date="2025-04-17">
    <description>
        <p>Changes in sizes to fix that our new responsive
        standards were broken because the main menu was
        not compiling with them.

        Fixing feedback labels to small in Hiragana and
        Katakana, Kanji remains broken in that sense...</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v1.12" date="2025-04-16">
    <description>
        <p>Fixes for Windows and adding XMPP as a possible communication mean.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v1.11" date="2025-04-15">
    <description>
        <p>Responsive fixes and clarifying the Kanji payment status.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v1.10" date="2025-04-14">
    <description>
        <p>Adding brand new website and porting to windows. Salud y República. Happy 4/14.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v1.09" date="2025-04-01">
    <description>
        <p>Adding setting fail penalty.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v1.08" date="2025-04-01">
    <description>
        <p>Adding the worst ever settings menu.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v1.07" date="2025-03-30">
    <description>
       <p>Updating to GNOME 48, perl 5.40.1 and updating every cpan library.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v1.06" date="2025-03-29">
    <description>
       <p>Fixing unable to see Japanese characters while having installed
        some system fonts. This error is known to happen in Tuxedo OS in
        version v1.05 while noto-cjk is uninstalled. (Thanks Vaun).</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v1.05" date="2024-12-13">
    <description>
       <p>Avoiding window resize on hiragana and katakana exercises.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v1.04" date="2024-12-02">
    <description>
       <p>Fixing bug unable to select specific level and decreasing number of simultaneus kanji to learn.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v1.03" date="2024-12-02">
    <description>
       <p>Improving further the description to make know users about they are supposed to fail when they are starting because I got a bad review complaining about that.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v1.02" date="2024-12-02">
    <description>
       <p>Indicating there is kanji support in the description.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v1.01" date="2024-12-02">
    <description>
       <p>Bugfix, avoiding blocking the program for a small time while waiting for the number of kanji characters to populate.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v1.00" date="2024-11-27">
    <description>
       <p>Adding BETA Kanji support.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v0.29" date="2024-11-13">
    <description>
       <p>Adding discord community to retrieve feedback from users.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v0.28" date="2024-11-10">
    <description>
       <p>Migrating to XS because Inline::C is giving compatibility issues.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v0.27" date="2024-11-09">
    <description>
       <p>Bundling noto-cjk by default to not having to ask users to install
        third party fonts.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v0.26" date="2024-07-13">
    <description>
       <p>Avoiding skip without reading the correct answer with a timeout.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v0.25" date="2024-07-13">
    <description>
       <p>Improving select buttons in dyslexia mode and general contrast.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v0.24" date="2024-07-13">
    <description>
       <p>Fixing regression nothing works because of uncommitted file.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v0.23" date="2024-07-13">
    <description>
       <p>Improving mode for dyslexia.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v0.22" date="2024-07-13">
    <description>
       <p>Adding mode for dyslexia.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v0.21" date="2024-07-07">
    <description>
       <p>Bugfix refactor unable to exit lesson.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v0.20" date="2024-07-07">
    <description>
       <p>Major refactor and new windows before entering a lesson and after leaving it.</p>
       <p>There is now an score that meassures how much effort you gave to the app.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v0.19" date="2024-07-05">
    <description>
       <p>The last small display fixes went badly this version tries to smooth that fixes.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v0.18" date="2024-07-05">
    <description>
       <p>On high score characters now the program can ask you to type the character in romanji, that's because it is very important that you can identify characters without clues.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v0.17" date="2024-07-05">
    <description>
       <p>Increasing adaptativity in small display devices.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v0.16" date="2024-07-04">
    <description>
       <p>Adding updated screenshots.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v0.15" date="2024-07-04">
    <description>
       <p>Exit lesson popup is now an adwaita alert, custom styles for light and dark themes.</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v0.14" date="2024-07-01">
    <description>
      <p>Adding branding colours</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v0.13" date="2024-07-01">
    <description>
      <p>Improving screenshots, adding the option to exit the lesson without exiting the program</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v0.12" date="2024-07-01">
    <description>
      <p>Adding a donation button, please use it</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v0.11" date="2024-07-01">
    <description>
      <p>Providing dark theme and using libadwaita to have better integration with GNOME</p>
    </description>
  </release>
  <release version="v0.10" date="2024-06-24">
    <description>
      <p>Initial version</p>
    </description>
  </release>
</releases>

  <developer id="me.sergiotarxz">
    <name>Sergiotarxz</name>
  </developer>
  
  <description>
    <p>This application helps you to learn Japanese characters using a gradual learning algorithm which makes you test-like questions.</p>

    <p>You are expected to fail while starting, look up the correct answer when you fail, it helps you to learn faster. You can use this app even if you do not know anything.</p>

    <p>This app pretends to be a way of learn but also somewhat of a game where you use your intuition and the previous things you learnt to avoid getting new characters
        wrong, but you are expected to fail because you won't have at all times all the needed information, your shouldn't feel overwhelmed because characters are 
        introduced gradually, but it can certainly happen that too much information is presented to you at once if you are too good memorizing, you can wipe
        ~/.var/app/me.sergiotarxz.JapaChar/config/.japachar/db.sqlite at any time to start over or change the settings to make the game more slow, fast or challenging
        depending on what do you want to get from this game.</p>

    <p>
      It keeps a inner score of how much you know a character to give priority to ask you again about it if needed and introduces new characters when you are ready.
    </p>

    <p>The BETA Kanji support now doesn't include (But did include in the past) KUN and ON readings since trying to memorize pronunciations of Kanji is discouraged for learners.</p>

    <p>New BETA Word memorizing support</p>

    <p>It works now without having to install any third party font.</p>
    
    <p>There is a settings menu that allows you to tune your learning further
    to your rithm, the numbers are saved with intro, if you leave a field empty
    you will restore the default, good if you mess up with the settings.</p>

    <p>This app doesn't and won't substitute studying the language using native texts, videos and audios, the goal is to reduce the initial barrier
        of entry since the written script is wildly different than the latin one.</p>

    <p>If you do not know any language based in latin script I cannot currently help you a lot with this app, sorry for that.</p>

    <p>It is boring to develop alone, get in contact in sergiotarxz@owlcode.tech over XMPP to contribute, I talk both Spanish and English.</p>

    <p>Do you have old phones around? It is very possible that some of them are capable of running Linux with Postmarketos, Mobian or Gentoo, try to test
        the app there and help me to improve it further.</p>

    <p>Would be nice to have sounds that I can put in the game to make it more engaging, if you are capable of designing Music or Sounds consider contributing
        your abilities for this free software app to continue improving.</p>
  </description>
  
  <launchable type="desktop-id">me.sergiotarxz.JapaChar.desktop</launchable>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://git.owlcode.tech/sergiotarxz/JapaChar/raw/commit/3de6ac7fef7c0dd6fadc5d96c3e627e7ebc111ae/Screenshot%20from%202024-11-27%2017-28-21.png</image>
      <caption>Success screen after resolving a katakana exercise</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://git.owlcode.tech/sergiotarxz/JapaChar/raw/commit/3de6ac7fef7c0dd6fadc5d96c3e627e7ebc111ae/Screenshot%20from%202024-11-27%2017-27-10.png</image>
      <caption>Main menu.</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://git.owlcode.tech/sergiotarxz/JapaChar/raw/commit/3de6ac7fef7c0dd6fadc5d96c3e627e7ebc111ae/Screenshot%20from%202024-11-27%2017-28-35.png</image>
      <caption>Failure screen</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://git.owlcode.tech/sergiotarxz/JapaChar/raw/commit/3de6ac7fef7c0dd6fadc5d96c3e627e7ebc111ae/Screenshot%20from%202024-11-27%2017-31-28.png</image>
      <caption>Kanji lesson select menu</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://git.owlcode.tech/sergiotarxz/JapaChar/raw/commit/13c912db257a2d18e3604081b6b57d2af6b65923/Screenshot%20from%202024-07-05%2001-40-51.png</image>
      <caption>Success on a guess romanji exercise</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://git.owlcode.tech/sergiotarxz/JapaChar/raw/commit/3de6ac7fef7c0dd6fadc5d96c3e627e7ebc111ae/Screenshot%20from%202024-11-27%2017-31-46.png</image>
      <caption>Kanji start lesson menu</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://git.owlcode.tech/sergiotarxz/JapaChar/raw/commit/3de6ac7fef7c0dd6fadc5d96c3e627e7ebc111ae/Screenshot%20from%202024-11-27%2017-31-53.png</image>
      <caption>Asking for kanji meaning</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://git.owlcode.tech/sergiotarxz/JapaChar/raw/commit/3de6ac7fef7c0dd6fadc5d96c3e627e7ebc111ae/Screenshot%20from%202024-11-27%2017-32-18.png</image>
      <caption>Asking for kanji Reading in On</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
</component>
